Contact

danmacalalag@yahoo.com

www.linkedin.com/in/danmacalalag (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Patient Safety
Patient Education
Patient Advocacy

Languages

English (Native or Bilingual)
Tagalog (Native or Bilingual)
Spanish (Limited Working)

Certifications

Chemotherapy & Biotherapy Provider CCRN

Dan Macalalag

Pediatric ICU BSN, RN, CCRN at Children's Hospital Los Angeles Greater Los Angeles Area

Summary

Experienced Pediatric Intensive Care Registered Nurse with a demonstrated history of working in the hospital & health care industry. Skilled in Public Speaking, Health Promotion, Acute Care, Teamwork, and Immunization. Strong healthcare services professional with a Bachelor's Degree focused in Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse from California State University-Los Angeles.

Experience

Children's Hospital Los Angeles (CHLA) Pediatric Intensive Care Unit, RN II September 2016 - Present (3 years 11 months) Los Angeles, California

Kaiser Permanente

2 years 6 months

Licensed Vocational Nurse February 2015 - November 2016 (1 year 10 months) Greater Los Angeles Area

Family Medicine, Los Angeles Medical Center

- Provide nursing care in accordance with the legal scope of practice and within established
- standards of care, policies, and procedures under the direct supervision of a RN or physician.
- Monitor patients' condition and notify physician/health care professional for disposition.
- Prepare and administer medications as directed by physician order following established protocols.
- Provide medical information and education to patients, following established protocols and guidelines.

- Explain purpose and process of examinations, tests, and medical procedures to patients.
- Review, explain, and clarify physician orders with patient.

Nurse Assistant

June 2014 - February 2015 (9 months)

Baldwin Park, CA

Medical-Surgical/Telemetry Unit, Baldwin Park

- Perform patient care activities within the scope of competency and under the supervision of RN.
- Collect data and provide information in a timely manner to the RN which may assist within the revision of the plan of care.
- Transport patients, equipment, supplies, and specimens throughout the medical center utilizing proper body mechanics.
- Promptly answer call lights, alarms, and patient requests.
- Participates in departmental performance improvement activities, i.e., planning, measuring/monitoring, assessing, and improving.

J & P Homes, Inc.

Licensed Vocational Nurse

December 2013 - September 2014 (10 months)

Buena Park, CA

- Provide patient care to developmentally delayed children per scope of nursing practice and facility policies and procedures.
- Measure and record patients' vital signs and notify charge nurse of any changes of a client's condition.
- Administer prescribed medications, perform proper documentation, and assess for adverse effects and side effects.
- Perform tracheostomy care such as changing the cannula, ties, and suctioning as needed or every other day.
- Supervise nurses' aides in providing basic patient care and delegate appropriate tasks.

Education

California State University-Los Angeles

Bachelor's Degree, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse (2013 - 2016)

Mt. San Antonio College

Pre-Nursing Studies · (2011 - 2013)

Hacienda La Puente Adult Education

Technical Degree in Vocational Nursing, Licensed Practical/Vocational Nurse Training \cdot (2009 - 2009)